Guide to the C.F. Quate Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
C.F. Quate papers
circa 1961-1984
SC0347
Quate, C.F.
13.5 Linear feet
Correspondence, memoranda, press releases, contracts, grants, course materials and other records pertaining to his research and teaching at Stanford, including work at the Ginzton Laboratory; and offsets, glossies, and slides from the acoustic microscope project.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Gift of Calvin F. Quate, 1987.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Calvin F. Quate earned his degrees in electrical engineering at the University of Utah (B.S., 1944) and Stanford University (Ph.D., 1950). He joined the Stanford faculty in 1961 as professor in the applied physics and electrical engineering departments, serving two terms as chair of the department of applied physics. He was Associate Dean of Humanities and Sciences from 1972-1974 and 1982-1983. In 1988 he received the IEEE's Medal of Honor for the invention of the scanning acoustic microscope.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, press releases, contracts, grants, course materials and other records pertaining to his research and teaching at Stanford, including work at the Ginzton Laboratory; and offsets, glossies, and slides from the acoustic microscope project.
Access Terms
Quate, C.F.; Stanford University. Department of Applied Physics. Faculty.; Stanford University. Department of Electrical Engineering. Faculty.; Acoustic microscopes.; Electrical engineering; Physics--Research.; Slides.
Collection Contents
- Papers, Accession ARCH-2004-117
  - Correspondence, 1986-90 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1991 Jan.-June (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1991 July-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1992 Jan.-March (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1992 May-July (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1992 Aug.-Sept. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1992 Oct.-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1993 Jan.-March (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1993 April-July (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1993 Oct.-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1994 Jan.-June (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1994 Aug.-Nov. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Jan.-April (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1995 May-Sept. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1995 Oct.-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Jan.-June (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1996 July-Sept. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1996 Oct.-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Personal correspondence, 1990-2001 (Box 2)
  - Biographical, miscellaneous (Box 2)
  - Medal of Science Award, press release, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Notebook, 1983 April- (Box 2)
  - Notebook, 1983 July- (Box 2)
  - Ginzton Lab Notebook, issued to C. F. Quate, Dec.21, 1992 (Box 2)
  - Quate, Traveling Wave Tubes as Low Noise Amplifiers, Ph. D. dissertation, Stanford University, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Certificates, etc.
    - The Royal Society, membership certificate, 1995 (Box 3 os)
    - IEEE Medal of Honor certificate, 1988 (Box 3 os)
    - National Academy of Science, membership certificate, 1975 (Box 3 os)
    - The Rank Prize for Opto-Electronics, 1982 (Box 3 os)
    - Joseph F. Keithley Award from the American Physical Society, 2000 (Box 3 os)
See also AM 2004-002, medals awarded to Quate:
IEEE Third Mellenium Medal, 2000
IEEE Medal of Honor 1988
National Medal of Science, 1992
National Medal of Technology
Aspen Highlands Silver Nastar